hey everyone welcome again to another
interesting Tosca lesson in this
particular session I am going to talk
about modules and how you can merge two
common or the same modules which are
present in your workspace now this is a
pretty common scenario when you're
working in a team uh with different
people working on the same project
so people tend to create uh modules on
their own right before checking whether
that module exists or not now there
could be different reasons for that uh
the one reason is if you have not
followed the naming conventions or
someone has not followed the naming
conventions while creating a module the
person who is trying to automate
something he may not recognize uh which
module is the correct one because the
naming is not proper or there could be
multiple modules with the same name
uh so it is difficult to find out if uh
the best practices are not followed
while working on a Tosca project it
might happen that there are multiple
modules doing the same exact thing right
and then it becomes very difficult to
manage uh if it is a large project and
if you have modules having the same
functionality or having the same names
it increases the workspace size and also
it becomes very difficult to manage
because if there is any change in the
module you probably have to change 100
modules right so it's always important
that you have unique modules uh for your
functionalities or for your controls and
if you find duplicate modules then you
should basically maintain them uh and
the Tosca provides a functionality where
you can merge uh the same modules which
have probably the same controls or even
if there are different controls it will
tell you that you can either delete the
controls or you can keep the controls
right so if there is any conflict can
also help you resolve it so it's always
better to maintain your modules in your
workspace uh so that it doesn't get out
of hand it will also affect your
performance and maintenance in the long
run okay
so for this purpose I have got this uh
Source demo login page module okay and
just to show you how it works I am going
to copy this and create some duplicate
modules here okay
and uh
then we are trying to merge these
modules so that uh we can have just one
module instead of having different
modules doing exactly the same thing
right
now to merge the modules uh go to the
modules Tab and there you will find a
merge modules option and also there is
an option to find duplicate modules okay
so first uh the module for which you
want to find duplicate modules just
select that module for us it is the
login page and click on find duplicate
modules Tosca will automatically search
the workspace and it will find all the
duplicate modules which are present okay
you can basically Set uh whichever
module you want as the target
and the source module would be the one
which you have selected okay so this is
our source module and then these are our
Target modules but uh
but you can set uh or you can select one
of these as the target modules okay
now once you do that once you select one
of the target modules uh this merge
selected option will be enabled now okay
and uh we can basically go ahead and
merge
merge the selected modules with the
source module
and it will perform some checks it will
check whether Target module was not
changed uh no usages were linked to the
Target module and then it is going to
delete the source module it is going to
rename the target module with the source
module so it will basically sort out
everything for you you don't need to do
anything
okay so if there are no controls which
are basically a conflict it will not
show any conflicts as well okay
so this is how easy it is to just merge
two different modules which probably
have the same controls and has been
using for the same functionality just
clean up your modules uh using this
merge module functionality right so
first you need to search for the
duplicate modules and then you can just
merge the source and the target module
foreign
what you can also do is you can select
two modules like this right so I have
got login page and login page underscore
two and once you do that uh it will this
merge modules uh option will get enabled
okay so once you select the two modules
and then you can click on merge module
again
so this time around you can see there
are different options here there is the
merge option that is the switch modules
option right and the show option
so here uh if you have got different
controls okay so it will show you which
controls you want to keep and which
controls you want to delete okay
so for example uh if I add
or I remove one of the controls here
okay so let's go to login page
underscore 2 and
let's remove this login button from here
okay now if I want to merge these two
modules okay
you can see here it is showing this is
the target module and this is the source
module okay I can change it so I can
switch the module so this becomes uh the
Target and this is the source okay
so what we can do is we can basically
change or we can remove or add any
controls which we want to keep on our
Target module okay so our Target module
is the final module right
so if you are using two modules uh which
we think are same we select those two
modules and then we look at the controls
which are present in those modules we
can either remove those or we can just
uh keep them okay in the Target module
so right now you can see uh all the
three controls are still present on my
target module now if I switch you can
see that this login button is not
present in my target module but it is
present in my source module so now if I
go ahead and merge these two modules uh
the login button would be removed right
I can even unlink this password and the
username fields from here okay
and then I can also again link them back
right so you can link and unlink
controls so you can basically decide
which controls you want to keep and
which you want to remove from your final
module okay and then uh I go ahead and
merge these two modules uh it will show
you that it has checked the change
rights right and uh the update one
module attribute in Target module uh the
following it will also uh basically
relink the usages so wherever you have
used them in your test cases it is going
to change them okay
and it is going to delete the source
module so that's what it is going to do
right
so as you can see now we have got this
one module uh obviously the name has
changed because we kept it as the target
module but this was just an example of
how you can do that okay so you can
basically uh merge two modules or you
can use the find duplicate modules
option to find the duplicate modules
which have probably the same name or
same controls
and then you can just merge them as per
your uh requirement okay so both of the
methods are fine uh how you want to do
it uh completely depends on you but it
is very important to clean up your
modules in your workspace especially if
you're working on a large project
so hope this was helpful uh and uh will
be coming up with more interesting
lessons on Tosca so keep looking
and don't forget to subscribe and hit
the Bell icon so that you get notified
when I post a new video on Tosca